Guide to the Beltway Poetry Quarterly records, 1990-2019 MS2389
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Beltway Poetry Quarterly records
1990-2019
2000-2019
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Beltway Poetry Quarterly
Roberts, Kim, 1961-
MS2389
4.25 Linear Feet 8 document boxes, 1 poster
Beltway Poetry Quarterly is an online literary journal and resource bank dedicated to poets and poetry in the Washington, DC area. The organization publishes two to three issues per year focused on different themes and authors. Beltway Poetry Quarterly was founded in 2000 by DC-based poet Kim Roberts. This collection contains poetry samples and submissions, administrative files, promotional and outreach materials, correspondence, and other project files.The material dates from 1990-2019, with the bulk of the material covering 2000-2019. While these records document the creative process and publication of the Beltway Poetry Quarterly journal, most were created by Kim Roberts, founder and editor (2000-2019).
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Box 8 of Series 2 contains restricted materials. Please contact Special Collections if you wish to consult these materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Kim Roberts, 2020 February 28 (2020.010)
Scope and Contents
This collection contains administrative files, promotional and outreach materials, correspondence, and other project files.The material dates from 1990-2019, with the bulk of the material covering 2000-2019. While these records document the creative process and publication of the Beltway Poetry Quarterly journal, most were created by Kim Roberts, founder and editor (2000-2019).
Biographical / Historical
Beltway Poetry Quarterly was founded in 2000 by Washington, DC-based poet, Kim Roberts. From their website: "Beltway Poetry Quarterly is an award-winning online literary journal and resource bank that showcases the literary community in Washington, DC and the surrounding Mid-Atlantic region. As the only journal in the region to focus solely on DC and surrounding jurisdictions, we are able to document a literary community in depth."
Beltway Poetry Quarterly publishes two to three issues per year. Some issues center on a specific theme, while others are groupings of authors and multiple poems from each. This second type of issue is called a "Portfolio." They also have occasional guest editors, who have been published before in a Portfolio issue.
In addition to producing the journal, Beltway Poetry Quarterly is a resource for poetry-related information and events in the DC-metro area. Many of those involved also act as advocates for literary issues and as historians who seek to preserve the legacy of poets who have lived and worked here.
The organization celebrated its twentieth anniversary in 2019. They published a special edition (Issue 20:4) that was a tribute to past guest editors.
Poetry -- 21st century; Poetry -- African American poets; Poets, American; Washington (D.C.); Publications; Internet publishing; Poetry--Editing; Roberts, Kim, 1961-
- Publication files, 2000-2019; 2000-2009; MS2389 Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  The materials of this series include files representing various editions of Beltway Poetry Quarterly, including correspondence, poetry drafts, and miscellaneous notes. They range in date from 2000-2019, with the bulk of materials from 2000-2009, and they represent the first nineteen years of Beltway Poetry Quarterly's publication.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically in order of Journal publication. Not every volume is represented. If users are looking for a specific volume that does not appear by volume and number, they should look for it under a subject or title (ie Museums issue).
  - Vol 1, No 1, 2000; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Vol 1, No 2, 2000 February-March, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 1, No. 3, 2000 May-June, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 1, No. 4 Merrill Leffler Ed., 2000 September-November, 2001 April, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Vol 2, No 1 Jan-March 2001, 2000 November-December; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Vol 2, No 2 April-June 2001, 2001 February-April, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Vol. 2, No. 3 Summer 2001, 2001 April-May, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Vol. 2, No. 4 Fall 2001 Brian Gilmore, Ed., 2001 June, August-September, December, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Vol. 3, No. 1 Winter 2002, 2001 September-December, 2002 January-February, 2003 February, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Vol. 3, No 2 Spring 2002, 1998 November, 2001 November, 2002 January-April, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Vol 3, No 3 Summer 2002, 2002 February, May, July, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Vol 3, No 4 Fall 2002 Hilary Tham, ED., 2002 March, July-August, October-November, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Vol 4, No 1 Winter 2003, 2002 April-May, November-December, 2003 January, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Vol 4, No. 2 Spring 2003, 2001 October, 2003 January-April, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Vol 4, No 3 Summer 2003, 2003 April-July; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Memory of Influence Vol 4, No 4 Fall 2003, 2001 July, 2003 March, July-August, October-November, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Vol 5, No 1 Winter 2004, 2003 May, October, December, 2004 January, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Vol 5, No 2 Spring 2004 Grace Cavalieri, ED., 2003 November-December, 2004 January-March, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Vol 5, No 3 Summer 2004, 2004 March-May, July, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Vol 5, No 4 Oct-Dec 2004, 2004 May-August, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Vol 6, No 1 Jan-Mar 2005 Whitman Issue, 2004 August-December, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Vol 6, No 2 April-June 2005 Naomi Ayala, ED., 2004 December, 2005 January-February, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Vol 6, No 3 July-Sept 2005, 2005 January-March, June, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Vol 6., No. 4 Oct-Dec. 2005, 2005 May-June, August, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Vol 7, No 1 Winter 2006, 2005 September, October, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vol 7, No 2 Poems on Iraq War April-June 2006 Spring 2006, 2005 December, 2006 June, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Vol 7, No 3 DC Places/Issue Summer 2006 July-Sept., 2006 January-July, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Vol 7, No 4 Profiles Issues Oct-Dec 2006 Fall 2006, 2006 April-June, August-September, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - [Class Assignments, Professor Liz Poliner], 2006 November; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Vol 8, No 1 Winter 2007, 2006 September-October; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Vol 8, No.2 Spring 2007, 2007 February-March; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vol 8, No 3 Summer 2007, 2007 February-March, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 8, No 4 Fall 2007 The Evolving City Teri Ellen Cross, co-editor [1/2], 2007 March-April, November, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 8, No 4 Fall 2007 The Evolving City Teri Ellen Cross, co-editor [2/2], 2007 March-April, November, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Vol 9, No 1 Split this Rock Winter 2008 Regie Cabico, Co-ed., 2007 October, 2008 March, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Vol 9, No 2 Spring 2008, 2008 January, March, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Vol 9, No 3 Literary Forebears Issue Summer 2008, 2007 November, 2008 May-June, September, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Vol 9/No 4 Audio Issue Fall 2008 Co-Editor: Katie Davis, 2007 February, 2008 September, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [Museum Issue] [1/3], 2008 August-September, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - [Museum Issue] [2/3], 2008 August-September, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - [Museum Issue] [3/3], 2008 August-September, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Vol 10:2 First Books Spring 2009 April-June, 2009 February-March, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - It's Your Mug Anniversary Issue//Vol 10:2 Guest Ed: Toni Asante Lightfoot//Spring 2009, 2009 March-April, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - US Poets Laureate Vol 10:4, 2008 August, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vol 11:1 Tenth Anniversary Issue Jan 2010 Winter, 2009 May-June, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mapping the City: DC Places II Volume 11:4 Winter 2010, 2010 January-March, May, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Hughes Issue Vol 12:1 Katy Richey, Co-Ed. Winter 2011, 2010 June, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Vol 13:2 Spring 2012, 2012 January-February, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Volume 14:2 Spring 2013, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Vol. 14:4 Oct-Dec 2013 Prose Poem Issue Abigail Beckel, 2013 July, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Orbit: The Asian American Issue Volume 15:3 Summer 2014, 2017 March, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Splendid Wake Issue Vol. 15:4, Fall 2014 Ed-Myra Sklarew, 2014 May, September-October, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sonnet Issue Vol 16:1 Winter 2015 Co-ed - Michael Gushue, 2014 August, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Translation Issue Vol. 16:3, Summer 2015 Co-Sponsored w/ DC-ALT, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sterling Brown Tribute Issue Vol. 18:4, Fall 2017, 2017 June-July, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Issue Vol 19:2 Spring 2019, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Vol 20:1, Jan-Mar 2019 US Poets Laureate, Part 2 Dan Vera, guest ed., 2018 November-December, undated; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Vol 20:3 Summer 2019 Portfolio Issue, 2019 April; MS2389 Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Administrative/Promotional materials, 1990-2019; 2000-2019; MS2389 Series 2
  - AWP [1/2], 2009-2011, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - AWP [2/2], 2009-2011, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Best of the Net Awards/Best of the Web Awards, 2010, 2018-2019, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Forthcoming, 2004-2005, 2015, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Future Poetry News, 2005, 2011-2014; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Letterhead, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Links [1/2], 1999-2004, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Links [2/2], 1999-2004, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Literary History of DC, 1998-2012, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 2015-2018, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Poetry News, 1999, 2000, 2003, 2010, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - PR/Marketing [1/3], 2002-2006, 2008, 2011-2014, 2019; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - PR/Marketing [2/3], 2002-2006, 2008, 2011-2014, 2019; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - PR/Marketing [3/3], 2002-2006, 2008, 2011-2014, 2019; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Promotional materials, 2009, 2019, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Promotional materials, 2012, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stationary/Press Releases, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Upcoming Issues [1/2], 1990, 1998, 2001-2006, 2008, 2009, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Upcoming Issues [2/2], 1990, 1998, 2001-2006, 2008, 2009, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 10th Anniversary, 2010, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - DC Humanities Council, 2002-2003, 2010, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - E-Address Books, 2004-2005, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Interns, 2002-2004, 2006, 2019, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Suscribers Mail List, 2000-2001, 2010, undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Beltway: A Poetry Quarterly [Poster], undated; MS2389 Series 2 (Oversize-folder 1, Item 1)